<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liz Corson</title>
    <description>Engineer, maker, and advocate for diversity in STEM.
</description>
    <link>http://lizcorson.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://lizcorson.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 17:56:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 17:56:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using MQTT to Monitor Temperature and Humidity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s having fun with the Internet of Things these days, and I’m joining in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to make an Intranet of Things using my own local MQTT broker. A couple months ago, I got a Raspberry Pi 3 and set it up with Raspbian Jessie Lite. I installed Mosquitto from the Debian repository, and voila, my own MQTT broker was up and running. I downloaded an MQTT app for my phone to subscribe and publish to whatever feeds I make. It really is very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first goal was to make a temperature/relative humidity sensor that would publish data to MQTT. Eventually I’d like to log these values somehow, maybe to a text file or a database, and make some kind of web dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got a chance to solder one of these together. It uses a cheap ESP8266 board from AliExpress and an HTU21D clone board for temperature and relative humidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/firstunit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of ESP8266 and HTU21D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app MQTT Dashboard lets you subscribe and publish, and it’s a great app with lots of features, like time series plots and a color picker. I highly recommend it. (Guess when I breathed on the sensor.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/mqttdashboard_feeds.png&quot; alt=&quot;Feeds&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/mqttdashboard_rhplot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time series plot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is available on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/lizcorson/mqtt_rht&quot;&gt;GitHub repository here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to make your own, here’s the schematic:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/esp8266_htu21d.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schematic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 17:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://lizcorson.github.io/2016/05/21/mqtt_rht.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lizcorson.github.io/2016/05/21/mqtt_rht.html</guid>
        
        <category>MQTT,</category>
        
        <category>IoT,</category>
        
        <category>ESP8266</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Color Mixer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In May I’ll be running a STEM workshop for Daisy and Brownie Girl Scouts. One of the activities is to teach them about the electromagnetic spectrum. We have a UV light demo using a blacklight and UV-sensitive beads, but I also wanted to add a more interactive component for visible light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a color mixer using a traditional RGB LED, with one pin per color channel, as well as a WS2812B LED. The student can turn each of three potentiometers to control the input of each of the R, G, and B channels. The goal is to demonstrate additive color mixing, since most kids are only familiar with subtractive color mixing as seen in paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to make some sort of case to neaten this up, but I may not have time. The code and a bill of materials are available in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/lizcorson/colormixer&quot;&gt;GitHub repository here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a schematic using Fritzing:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/colormixer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schematic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the whole thing:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/wholesystem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole system&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a closeup of the circuit board:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/boardcloseup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Circuit board closeup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is a demo of the color mixing, red -&amp;gt; magenta -&amp;gt; white.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/redonly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Red LED&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/mix-magenta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Magenta LED&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lizcorson.github.io/assets/colormixer/mix-white.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White LED&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 14:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://lizcorson.github.io/2016/04/23/colormixer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lizcorson.github.io/2016/04/23/colormixer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Girl</category>
        
        <category>Scouts,</category>
        
        <category>Arduino</category>
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I’m Liz, and while I’m a chemical engineer by trade, I’ve always enjoyed programming and playing with computers. I’ve also recently gotten into hobby electronics after taking a course which required the use of an Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started this blog to document my projects in a better format than just uploading them to GitHub. I’ll be using microcontrollers, laser cutting, and 3D printing to build all sorts of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, I’m interested in building and programming devices that interact with the physical world, both profesionally and for fun. I’m looking forward to building things that are both fun and useful and experimenting with the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also volunteer to encourage kids, especially those from groups underrepresented in engineering, to pursue careers in STEM. We need new ideas and new paradigms in STEM, and ensuring that people of all races, genders, sexualities, etc, can contribute will result in a better future for us all. I do outreach with the Society of Women Engineers towards that end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 17:41:51 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://lizcorson.github.io/intro/2016/04/10/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lizcorson.github.io/intro/2016/04/10/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
